字幕转制｜天外生物
感谢原字幕制作者
坠入
伊芙琳护士！伊芙琳护士！
Nurse Evelyn! Nurse Evelyn!
我有讯息要跟你说，用英文写的！
I have a message for you. In English!
就是这个
And here we go.
看看，这是上个月以来所有病人的名单
Now, look, here's the list of all the patients we've had in the ward in the last month.
谢谢，护士
Thank you, Nurse.
- 你是亚历珊卓？ - 是的
- You're Alexandria?  - Yes.
你的纸条飞进来，掉在我的膝部
Your note came in, and landed on my lap.
完全看不懂，是胡乱涂鸦还是什么的
Couldn't even understand it. It's written in gibberish or something.
你看不懂，对吗！你看不懂，那不是写给你的
You didn't understand it, didn't you, didn't understand it, it's not for you.
我叫罗依
My name's Roy.
- 你是怎么伤了手臂的？ - 我跌了下来
- How'd you hurt your arm?  - I fell.
我也是
Me too.
当时我在采橘子
I was picking oranges.
是那样吗？
Is that so?
那你要如何上厕所？
How do you go to the potty?
我不用去，他们让我在这里上
I don't. They let me go right here.
- 在床上？ - 是呀！是真的
- In bed?  - Yeah, it's true.
我不相信
I don't believe.
嘿！亚历珊卓
Hey, Alexandria.
嘿！你知道你的名字是根据阿历山大大帝的名字取的？
Hey, do you know you're named after Alexander the Great
他是史上最伟大的战士喔！
who was the greatest warrior who ever lived?
是的，我的纸条不是随便涂鸦，那是英文！
Yes. And my note is not in gibberish. It's in English!
嘿！我可以看到你，快过来这
Hey, I can see you. Come on out here.
我看见你躲在那
I can see you hiding.
亚历珊卓
Alexandria.
嘿！你知道亚历山大也在等待讯息吗？
Hey, did you know he was also looking for a message?
他迷路了
He was lost.
几乎要死了，跟他的大军走散了
He almost died, separated from his army.
- 他收到讯息了吗？ - 什么？
- Did he find the message?  - What?
后来他有收到讯息吗？亚历山大大帝
Did she find the message? Alexandria the Great.
好好，我告诉你，你过来
All right, right, I'll tell you, just come in here.
过来，抓把椅子过来坐下
Now, come on, grab that chair right there.
好的，别弄断了另一条手臂
All right, don't break your other arm.
- 谢谢  - 不客气
- Thank you.  - You're welcome.
- 盒子里有什么？ - 我喜欢的东西
- What's in your box?  - Things I like.
- 是你偷的吗？ - 不
- Things you stole?  - No.
是照片
A photo.
你那来的大象？
Where'd you get the elephant?
我朋友送的
My friend gave it to me at work.
他是印度人
He's from India.
看，这是我的马
Look, this is my horse
- 这是我的父亲  - 是吗？
- and this is my father.  - Yeah?
他的门牙中间有缝隙，这应该是你们家族的特征
He's got the same gap in his teeth, must run in the family.
- 是呀！这是我家  - 是吗？
- Yeah, and here is my house.  - Oh, yeah?
- 这曾经是我家  - 怎么了？
- It was my house.  - What happened?
- 他们烧了它  - 谁？
- They burn it.  - Who burned it?
愤怒的人们
Angry people.
听到这我很难过
I'm sorry to hear that.
我说，听到这我很难过
I said, I'm sorry to hear that.
愤怒的人们
Angry people.
是呀！我知道，听到你的房子被烧了我很难过
Yeah, I know, I'm just sorry that your house got burned.
为何阿历山大
Why did Alexander
没有从建筑物里面骑马出来？
didn't go from that buildings on his horse?
- 若是他迷路了…  - 什么？
- If him was lost...  - What?
为何阿历山大不从房里面骑马出来？
Why did Alexander didn't go from that middle of the buildings from that buildings on his horse?
嗯…
Well...
首先，他没有马，因为他的马在战争中死了
First of all, he didn't have a horse because his horse was killed in a battle.
况且，他也不是在任何房子里
And he wasn't in the middle of any old buildings.
而是在广大沙漠中迷路了，四周尽是橙黄色的沙子
He was lost in the middle of a vast desert, full of orange sand
身边只有几个随从
with only a handful of men
但是他们连一滴水也没有
but they didn't have any water.
看！
Look!
“大人，一切希望都没了
"My Lord, all hope is lost.
“似乎您的大军终将被征服
"It seems your mighty army shall finally be conquered.
“不是被波私人，而是被缺水所打败
"Not by the Persians, but by our own greed and gluttony for water.
“这顶头盔，就是我们仅能提供的
"This helmet contains our last supply.
“喔！大王，我相信你的智慧将会让我们得救”
"Oh, King, I believe your wisdom shall save us all."
- 为什么？ - 为什么？
- Why?  - Why?
什么？
What?
为什么？
Why?
因为水不够所有人喝
Well, because there wasn't enough water for all of them
而且那就是阿历山大大帝做事的方法
and it was Alexander the Great's way
像他的军队显示他们一切平等…
of showing his army that they were all equal...
真是蠢啊
It's stupid.
那你会怎样做比较好？
What would you do better?
阿历山大为什么把水倒掉
Was Alexander throw the water
而不是给每个人都喝一小口呢
instead to give every soldier a little bit.
嘿！你何不明天再来，我再跟你说另个故事
Hey, why don't you come back tomorrow and I'm going to tell you a different story.
史诗般的爱情与复仇故事
An epic tale of love and revenge.
- 你知道“史诗般”是什么意思吗？ - 不知道
- You know what "epic" means?  - No.
我这里仍然闷闷的，好像连…
I still got this tightness here. It's like I can't even...
那表示是个很长的故事，而且发生在印度
It means a really long story, and it's set in India.
…好像胸口有只大象那样沉重
...the elephant sitting on my chest.
- 你将会很快好转的  - 好的，继续
- You should be fully recovered.  - All right, go on.
- 我要你帮我检查  - 你明天会在来吗？
- I want you to examine me.  - Will you come back tomorrow?
我觉得不太好
You personally. I'm not very well.
肿胀似乎消了点
The swelling seems down.
我知道那很痛
I know how much it hurts.
幽默一下
A sense of humor.
几周后疼痛会消失，然后在做一次手术
In the next couple of weeks the pain should abate, then one more operation.
跟上次一样吗？
Like the last one?
这需要你的努力，知道吗？
This is going to take some effort on your part, too, you know that?
看见没？
See?
过来
Come on, then.
- 午餐前回来  - 好的
- Be back before lunch.  - Okay.
亚历珊卓，离开那冰块
Alexandria, get away from that ice.
我看到你舔冰块，你会生病的
I see you licking that ice, you're gonna get sick.
去别地方玩！
I want you to go play, go!
下次我会将你的舌头黏在冰块上将你载走
Next time, I'll glue your lips to this and carry you away.
只有马死了你要觉得幸运了
You're lucky it was just a horse that got killed.
我是说，从铁道桥上跳下来，无疑是自杀
I mean, jumping off a train bridge was suicide, too.
若是你想要上她印象深刻…
And if you were trying to impress her...
辛克莱比较吸引她
Sinclair already did a better job.
你知道，那男演员
You know, the actor,
- 男主角  - 我知道他是谁
- the leading man.  - I know who he is.
只有熬过困难才会有拨云见日的一天，那是一定的
Every cloud has a silver lining, that's for sure.
拿另外一张牌
Take another card.
- 在我发生意外前…  - 那是红心Q
- You know, before my accident...  - That is the Queen of Hearts.
…事事顺利
...nothing was happening for me.
现在我的腿被粗鲁的人砍伤
Now I've had my leg hacked off by savages,
被马车压过，然后被锯掉
mangled by chariots, sawed off by lumberjacks.
嗯，还被一只鱼叉穿过，我一直在工作
Hell, I've even had a harpoon through it. I'm working all the time.
这是黑桃二
That is the two of spades.
- 片场正想要补偿你  - 抱歉，沙巴提尼先生
- The studio is just trying to do right by you.  - Excuse me, Mr. Sabatini.
钱就收下吧
Take the money.
无论如何，娱乐圈不适合你，罗依
Anyway, gags are not for you, Roy.
你该是个读书人
You're a college man.
我不是
Wasn't me.
一个瘸子的忠告…
One cripple to another...
我没有朝你丢橘子
I didn't throw orange at you.
…没有女人值得为她自杀
...no woman is worth suicide.
想要跟那人一样当明星，看在老天的分上
Like the guy's a movie star, for chrissake.
你的朋友是个海盗吗？
Was your friend a pirate?
有时候是
Sometimes.
他当海盗才伤了脚？
Is that how he hurt his leg?
不，他…他为电影做特技
No, he... He does tricks for pictures.
就是电影啊
You know, flickers.
动画片
Moving pictures.
- 我没看过电影  - 你也没错过什么啦
- I never seen one.  - You're not missing much.
你也跟你朋友做一样的工作吗？
Is that what you do, like your friend?
只做了一次
Just once.
现在可以跟我说故事了吗？
Will you tell me the story now?
- 什么故事？ - 史诗故事啊
- What story?  - The epic.
好吧
All right.
好，闭上眼睛
All right, close your eyes.
你看到什么？
What do you see?
什么都没有
Nothing.
柔一柔
Rub them.
看到星星没有？
Can you see the stars?
是的
Yes.
那是一个多星的夜晚
It was a starry night.
四个人在一个小岛上焦急地等着
Four men waited impatiently on a small island
四周海水平静无声
surrounded by a calm sea.
但是这平静是假的
But that calmness was deceptive.
因为在那时候
For at that moment
有个腿绑绷带的印度人，朝向他们游了过来
an Indian with a bandaged thigh swam towards them.
告诉我，印度人
Tell me, Indian.
是真的吗？
Is it true?
路易奇，什么是真的？
Luigi, is what true?
欧迪亚斯总督明天将会将你的孪生哥哥处死
Governor Odious will execute your twin brother tomorrow morning.
我可怜的哥哥
My poor brother.
现在他们有五个人
In all, there were five of them.
他们只有一个共通点
They had only one thing in common,
憎恨欧迪亚斯总督
a hatred of Governor Odious.
第一个人以前是个奴隶，奥塔・班加
The first was an ex-slave, Otta Benga.
他与他哥哥生而为奴隶
He and his brother were born into slavery
工作只是为了填满邪恶欧迪亚斯总督的金库而已
only to fill the coffers of the evil Governor Odious.
有天他正在田里做苦力…
One day while toiling in the fields...
因为哥哥的死伤心至极，他释放了其他奴隶
Heartbroken at his brother's death, he freed the slaves
发誓他要亲自杀死欧迪亚斯总督
and swore that he would be responsible for Governor Odious's death.
我喜欢他
I like him.
然后是印度人
Then, there was the Indian,
当他紧张时，总是会拨弄眉毛
who, whenever anxious, always stroked his brow.
印度人原本要娶世界上最美的女人
The Indian was supposedly married to the most beautiful squaw in the world
但是没人见过这女人
yet nobody had seen her.
为了证实，他伪装成q疯病患者
To verify this, Odious disguised himself as a leper
他见到她的倒影时，立刻为她神魂颠倒
but when he saw her reflection, he was smitten.
锁住他的小屋，印度人持续看守着
Locking the doors to his wigwam, the Indian stood guard.
但是他不知道，他看守的是个空屋
Little did he know, he was guarding an empty home
因为他的妻子已经被欧迪亚斯总督所绑架
for his wife had already been kidnapped by the evil Governor Odious.
但是那女人拒绝了总督
But the squaw refused to show herself to him.
欧迪亚斯将她送进“绝望迷宫”里面去
So, Odious had her thrown into the Labyrinth of Despair.
她终于明白，唯一的出路是
Eventually she realized there was only one way out.
因为妻子的死
While mourning his wife's death
印度人发了血誓，决不再看其他女人一眼
the Indian took a blood oath never to look at another squaw
发誓他要亲自杀死欧迪亚斯总督
and that he would be responsible for Governor Odious's death.
我也喜欢他
I like him, too.
路易奇是炸药专家
Luigi was an explosive expert.
当欧迪亚斯听说了他的新式炸药的威力
When Odious heard about the power of his new bombs,
他将他从公开场合带走
he had him publicly banished.
他回来后，路易奇发现所有的人都躲着他
On his return, Luigi discovered that everybody hid from him
因为连跟他说话，也会招致杀身之祸
because even speaking to him was punishable by death.
当连他的神父也拒绝听他告解之后
But when his own priest refused to hear his confession,
路易奇发誓他要亲自杀死欧迪亚斯总督
Luigi swore that he would be responsible for Governor Odious's death!
下一个是英国自然科学家
Next was the English naturalist
查尔斯・达尔文
Charles Darwin.
他热爱生命
He loved all living things,
动物，植物，所有生物
creatures, plants, everything alive.
达尔文有个害羞又聪明的伴
Darwin was always accompanied by his shy, brilliant colleague,
猴子华乐斯
Wallace the monkey.
那是什么，华乐斯？
What is that, Wallace?
我不知道为何火鹤全身粉红
I don't know why flamingos are pink.
虽然他们一起已经发现了许多理论
Even though they had developed many theories together
他们仍持续寻找
they were still looking for something.
- 什么？ - 蝴蝶
- What?  - Butterfly.
猜的好
That's a good guess.
是一种非常特殊的蝴蝶
In fact, a very specific butterfly
叫做“新美洲蝶”
called Americana Exotica.
有一天，欧迪亚斯寄给他一只死掉的
One day, Odious sent them a dead one.
蝴蝶礁
Butterfly Reef.
欧迪亚斯，是个坏人吗？
This Odious, it's bad man?
喔！是呀！
Oh, yeah.
蝴蝶礁
Butterfly Reef.
欧迪亚斯总督就是将这些人放逐在那
That's where Governor Odious chose to banish our heroes,
要他们绝望
to mock them,
希望他们在挣扎生存的过程中会自相残杀
hoping that in their fight for survival they would devour each other.
所以，这些buccaneer（海盗）就在这珊瑚礁上
So, the buccaneers were trapped on this island.
什么是buccaneer？
What means a buccaneer?
就是海盗一样的意思
Well, it's like a pirate. Pirate and buccaneer, it's like the same thing.
但我不喜欢海盗的故事
But I don't like pirate stories.
是你叫我说海盗故事的
You're the one who asked for a pirate story.
- 我没有  - 你有
- No.  - Yes, you did.
我只是想问，你朋友是不是海盗
I just wanted to know if your friend was a pirate.
- 为什么？ - 因为他只有一条腿
- Why?  - Because he has just one leg.
喔！
Oh, right.
是呀！那不是海盗故事，那是强盗的故事
Well, yeah, it's not a pirate story. It's a story about bandits.
事实上，我们的蒙面侠，不会游泳
In fact, our masked hero couldn't even swim.
我要学游泳
I need to learn to swim.
最后，门牙有缝的蒙面侠
Finally, very little was known about the gap-toothed Masked Bandit.
- 跟我父亲一样？ - 就像是父亲
- Like my father?  - Yes, your father.
但是他有个孪生兄弟，蓝侠
Except that he and his twin brother, the Blue Bandit,
蓝侠逃过了西班牙欧迪亚斯总督的处死令
had escaped execution from the Spanish Governor Odious.
因为知道他们最好分头逃亡
Knowing that their chances of survival were better apart
生存机会比较大，他们分开了
the two brothers separated
发誓他们将会亲手杀死欧迪亚斯总督
swearing that they would kill Governor Odious.
我们该来计划一下
We must conceive a plan!
我要逃离这个岛，拯救我兄弟
I need to get off this island, and rescue my twin brother.
什么？什么？
What? What?
大象？
All elephants?
我说，我们…
I say, we...
我有主意了
I have an idea.
达尔文！真是个好点！
Darwin! That was a great idea!
快，奥塔・班加！
Come on, Otta Benga!
再见，朋友，游的愉快！
Goodbye, my beautiful friend! Have a nice swim!
达尔文，你真是天！
Darwin, you are a genius!
非常感谢！
Much obliged!
你的点子怎么想到的？
Where do you get these ideas?
那是什么，朋友？
What is it, my friend?
真可怜，这男人疯了
How sad. The tortures of this world have driven the poor man mad.
不是的
Not true.
他说他是由神秘教派所派来
He said he has been sent by his mystic cult
帮助我们对抗欧迪亚斯总督跟他的西班牙党羽
to help us against Governor Odious and his Spanish henchmen.
这地方原本是座森林，到处是鸟儿与树木
This region was once a lush forest alive with birds and sacred trees
但欧迪亚斯将他们都烧掉了
but Odious had them all burned down.
欧迪亚斯总是说鸟儿在肚子里面比较安全
He also says the birds are safe inside his belly
但是我们要小心，因为适者生存的法则
but we must take care for only the fittest shall survive.
告诉他我们不了解神秘教
Tell him we have no use of a mystic.
我们正在执行一个危险任务
We are on a dangerous mission.
我们要快去城里面，拯救我兄弟
We need to hurry to the fort to save my twin brother.
他会拖慢我们的
He will only slow us down.
鱼，男士们！
Fish, ser!
靠边，朋友
Stand aside, my friend.
在你一眨眼之前，我就可以将这门打开
Before you say kaboom, I have this door open.
饶恕我，伟大的教主，原谅我的不敬
Forgive me, wise mystic, for my disrespect.
毫无疑问的，你有战争的天份
Undoubtedly, you have a flair for war-mongering.
若是你能加入我们的行列
It would be my honor if you consider joining us
那将是我们极大的荣耀
on our quest.
我们要拯救我兄弟！
We must save your brother!
首先
First,
小小册是
a little test.
你不可以在这中断
You can't stop there.
我只是想玩个小测验，我要你去摸我的脚趾头
I just wanna play a little game. I want you to go outside and touch one of my toes.
不，我要听故事，后来蓝侠怎么了？
No, tell me the story. What happened with the Blue Bandit?
不会很久的
It won't take long.
- 到床尾，去摸我的脚趾  - 好的
- Just go outside and touch one of my toes.  - Okay.
- 我在摸你的小趾  - 不！
- I'm touching your little toe.  - No!
别告诉我，你摸那一趾，让我猜
Please don't tell me which toe you're touching. I gotta guess.
那是游戏的重点
That's the whole point of the game. All right.
我在摸了
I'm touching one.
你在摸大拇趾？
You're touching my big toe?
你是说真的吗？
Are you telling the truth?
看
Look.
真的
Really.
喔！我猜对了？
Oh, I got that?
怎么了？
What happened?
他兄弟怎么了？有被救出来吗？
What happened with his brother? Did he save him?
不，不，不，你是在说笑吗？
No, no, no, no. Were you telling a story?
不，不，不，你是说真的吗？
No, no, no. Were you telling the truth just now?
我是说真的
No. I was telling the truth.
不，你说假话
No. You just said no, you weren't telling the truth.
不，我说得是真的
No, I tell you it.
- 你说真的吗？ - 是呀！
- Were you telling the truth?  - Yeah.
当你摸我脚趾的时候？
When you just touched my toe?
- 你这小骗子  - 不是
- You little liar.  - No.
亚历珊卓，你有骗我吗？
Alexandria, were you lying to me?
我摸你的大姆指
I touch your big toe.
我们要快点！
We need to hurry!
你要我说完故事吗？
Do you want me to finish the story?
蒙面侠太晚抵达吊灯大厅
The Masked Bandit arrived at the Chandelier Hall too late.
欧迪亚斯已经折磨了他兄弟与同党
Odious had already tortured his brother and crew
并且吊死他们
and hung them.
好，够了！这里不是马戏团，也不是你们的游乐场…
All right, that's it! It's not a circus. It's not a playground for all your...
够了！听见没？
Please! Are you listening to me?
滚出去！
Get out of here!
- 你放开他  - 过来，宝贝
- You leave her alone.  - Come here, baby.
走开！去你的！
Get off! Goddamn!
不，不，宝贝，过来，过来
No, no, no, sweetheart, come here, come here. Come on.
爸爸？
Dad?
- 爸爸？爸爸？ - 我觉得不太舒服
- Dad? Dad?  - I'm not feeling real well.
- 你要什么？ - 他又来了
- What do you want?  - He's doing it again.
停下来？放开他！
Will you stop that? Leave him alone!
- 那是什么？ - 食物
- What's that?  - Food.
- 那里拿的？ - 教堂
- Where'd you get it?  - The chapel.
很抱歉我对你大吼大叫
I'm sorry I shouted at you.
当时我太生气
I was angry.
没关系
No problem.
你是在拯救我的灵魂吗？你是在拯救我的灵魂吗？
Are you trying to save my soul? Are you trying to save my soul?
- 你听的懂吗？ - 什么？
- Do you understand me?  - What?
- 你懂我的意思吗？ - 你说什么？
- Did you understand what I meant?  - What you said?
我说，你是在拯救我的灵魂吗？
I said, are you trying to save my soul?
- 给我那个  - 什么那个？
- Giving me that.  - What mean that?
圣餐，那是…
The Eucharist. It's a...
什么？
What?
圣餐，你给我的东西…
The Eucharist. The thing you gave me. It's a...
可以拯救你的灵魂
It saves your soul.
我给你的东西，什么？
The thing I gave to you, what?
你给我的一小块面包，拯救我的灵魂
The little piece of bread that you just gave me.
可以拯救你的灵魂
It saves your soul.
- 什么？什么？什么？ - 你担心我吗？
- What? What? What?  - Are you worried about me?
拯救你的灵魂，你知道“灵魂”是什么意思吗？
Saves your soul. Do you know what "soul" means?
- 不  - 像是力量一样
- No.  - It's like strength.
为何那老人晚上要将牙齿放在杯子里？
Why does the old man keep his teeth in a glass at night?
那是他保存力量的方法，他的灵魂
It's where he keeps his strength, his spirit.
他的灵魂在那牙齿里？
His spirit is in those teeth.
是呀！
Yeah.
喔！你现在失去了一些力量
Oh, you're missing a little strength
就在你的嘴巴前面
right in the front of your mouth.
教堂在大道上，是吗？
The chapel's in the main block, isn't it?
是的，蒙面侠怎么了？
Yes. What happened with the Black Bandit?
很抱歉
I'm sorry.
没事
It's okay.
他们都将药物存放再大街上，是吗？
They keep the medicine in the main block, don't they?
是的
Yes.
从我身上拿走的，是无法取代的
That which has been taken from me can never be replaced.
我的兄弟…
My brother...
- 为何他要这样说？ - 因为他是你父亲
- Why he speaks like this?  - Because he's your father.
但父亲死了
But my father is dead.
什么？
What?
好，那你要我…那你要我怎么说话？
Okay, how do you want me... How do you want him to speak?
我想到我们一起的快乐时光
I think of all the joys we had.
正常的说话，像你一样
Normal, like you.
我没有来得及救你，因为当时我虚弱
I could've saved you, but I was weak.
我的悲伤以化成血染的复仇
My grief has gone blood-red with revenge.
我现在已经更强壮
I'm stronger now.
我会在世上各个角落找寻欧迪亚斯总督的踪迹，然后杀掉他！
I will search the four corners of this Earth, find Governor Odious and joyously kill him!
以蓝侠之名，我在此发誓
By the Blue Bandit's honor, I swear
我会歼灭他，还有他的所爱！
I will annihilate him and everything that he loves!
我会歼灭他！我会歼灭他！
I will destroy him! I will destroy him!
我会歼灭他！歼灭他！
Destroy him! I will destroy him!
还有所有西班牙的东西
And every Spanish thing.
我还以为他是西班牙人
I thought he was Spanish.
不
No.
他是法国人
He was French.
你们跟我同一阵线吗？
Are you with me, bandits?
达尔文！要怎么去找欧迪亚斯总督？
Darwin! Which way to Governor Odious?
我跟他说过，别将地图跟虫子放在一起
I tell him not to put the map with the bugs.
我们迷路了吗？
Are we lost?
抱歉，队长
Sorry, Capitaine.
嘿！不！
Hey! No!
嘿！你不可以吃，那有毒！
Hey! You can't eat it, it's poisonous!
他说什么？
What's he saying?
他说跟着他，可以到青翠葱绿的牧场！
He says we should follow him to greener pastures!
- 什么？ - 他说下面有青翠葱绿的牧场
- What?  - He say it's greener down there.
绿洲？下面？
Green? Down where?
我不知道
I don't know.
青翠葱绿的牧场！
To greener pastures!
慢点！
Slow down!
他肚子里的鸟儿渴望着绿洲！
The birds in his belly crave greener pastures!
嘿！青翠葱绿的牧场
Hey! It is greener down there.
青翠葱绿的牧场
Greener pastures.
慢点！
Slow down!
别跑！越跑毒性发作越快！
Please don't run! The poison works faster if you run!
慢点
Slow down.
那有毒
It's poisonous.
什么？
What?
他在指引我们方向
He's giving us directions.
去！
Go!
奴隶！
Slaves!
欧迪亚斯的旗帜
Odious's flag.
我们要是放那些奴隶
We must free the slaves.
告诉我，亚历珊卓，你会看英文吗？
Tell me, Alexandria, do you read English?
你总是在最美好，
You always stop at the same part when it's very beautiful
最有趣的时候停下来
and interesting.
我想知道你会不会看英文
I just wanted to know if you can read English.
会吗？
Can you?
- 你会看英文吗？ - 是呀！
- Can you read English?  - Yeah.
- 这是什么？ - 纸
- What's this?  - Paper.
不，这是什么？这个
No. What's this? This.
M，o，r，p，h…
M-o-r-p-h...
三
Three.
- 那是什么？ - 三
- What's that?  - Three.
很好
That's good.
我一直睡不好，故事不记得了
I'm having a hard time sleeping and I can't remember that story.
我需要一些药物
I need some pills.
我需要的药物，装在写有这些字的瓶子里面
I need pills in a bottle that has this written on them.
M，o，r，p，h，i，n，三？
M-o-r-p-h-i-n-three?
是的，而且就在大道上
Yes. And it's in the main block.
大街上的房间里
In that room in the main block.
懂吗？
You understand?
- 问问护士长  - 我是以朋友的身份求你
- Ask the head nurse.  - I'm asking you as a friend.
- 但那是偷窃  - 不，若是你需要，就不是偷
- But it's stealing.  - No, it's not. Not if you need it.
那跟从教堂偷面包没有差别
It's no different than stealing bread from a church.
- 我去帮你问他们  - 不
- I'll ask them for you.  - No.
那是同伙的秘密
It's a bandit secret.
我需要那药丸，才能继续说故事，懂吗？
I need the pills to finish the story. Understand?
- 我拿不到…  - 我会去做
- I can't get it...  - I'll do it.
谢谢
Thanks.
你看起来好漂亮
You look beautiful.
你为何在脸颊上擦上红色？
Why do you put red on your cheeks?
因为那会让你看来更漂亮
Because it makes you look pretty
也更健康
and healthy, too.
- 记得，午餐前回来  - 我知道！
- Remember, back before lunch.  - I know!
亚历珊卓，今天没有舔冰块？
Alexandria, no licking the ice today?
没有，谢谢！再见！
No. Thank you! Bye!
也许咬一口，但是一窝蛇？
One bite maybe. But a pit of snakes?
[药房]
M，o，r，p，h，i，n，三，M，o，r，p，h，i-n…
M-o-r-p-h-i-n-three. M-o-r-p-h-i-n...
M，o，r，p，h，i，n…
M-o-r-p-h-i-n...
也许你…我知道，听我的很重要
Maybe you got... I know it's important that you listen to me.
你也该想想你的其他孩子
You've gotta think of your other children.
很抱歉
I'm so sorry.
你该警告其他孩子，有关响尾蛇的声音
You have to warn your other children about the sounds of rattlesnakes.
这不是好时机，这附近到处有蛇窝
This isn't a good time. There are snake pits all over this area.
醒醒！醒醒！快起来，否则他们会砍你
Wake up! Wake up! You better get up or they'll chop you.
快起来！你最好快起来，让他们知道你只是在睡觉
You get up! You better get up and show these people you are sleeping.
你不起来那人会剁了你，快起来！
These men will chop you if you don't get up. Get up!
快起来，不是开玩笑
Get up. This isn't funny.
求你，离开这里
Please, let's leave this place.
来！
Come on. Come on!
我一直都那样做
I do that all the time.
你要做的就是换掉湿的衣服，将他们藏起来直到干了为止
All you have to do is change your clothes and hide the wet ones until they're dry.
你知道我遇到可怕的事情时，我怎么做吗？
You know what I do when something frightens me?
我就说神奇咒语
I say the magic words.
走开，走开，走开，走开
Googly, googly, googly, begone.
我们来一起练习
Let's practice together.
神奇咒语
The magic words.
走开，走开，走开
Googly, googly, googly. Go away.
- 你拿到我要你拿的东西吗？ - 是的
- Did you get what I sent you for?  - Yes.
- 这个  - 是吗？
- This it is.  - Yeah?
里面只有三个
There's only three in here.
- 你叫我拿三个  - 不，我叫你拿一整瓶
- You asked me for three.  - No, I asked you for a full bottle.
- 但，你写的…  - 这瓶子里有满满的吗？
- But, you wrote...  - Was this bottle full of pills?
- 里面有更多药丸吗？ - 是呀！
- Were there more pills in here?  - Yeah.
那你拿去哪了？
What did you do with them?
丢进马桶里面了
I throw them in toilet.
因为你写三个，我才丢掉其他的
But I throw them away because you wrote
m-o-r-p-h-i-n-三
m-o-r-p-h-i-n-three.
这可以帮你入眠吗？
Will they help you sleep?
可以小睡一下
A nap perhaps.
我们要解放奴隶
We must free the slaves.
他们有解放了奴隶吗？
Did they free the slaves?
出来，欧迪亚斯
Come out, Odious.
像只蝴蝶
Just like a butterfly.
为何又戴面具？
Why the mask again?
他不想吓到她
He doesn't want to scare her.
她对他一无所知，但是他却知道她的所有事情
She doesn't know anything about him, but he knew everything about her.
眼睛的颜色
The color of her eyes.
棕色
Brown.
她最爱的食物
Her favorite food.
橘子？
Orange?
她最喜欢的书
Her favorite book.
圣经
Bible.
各位，她是我的
Boys, she's mine.
- 炸弹怎么了？ - 什么？
- What about the bomb?  - What?
炸弹
The bomb.
强盗们绑架了公主，留下了她的小表妹
The bandits kidnapped the princess, leaving behind her little nephew.
他们从高山上骑马下山
They rode down from the high mountain deserts
到了他喜爱的地方
to a place he loved.
他跟他孪生兄弟玩耍的地方
He had played as a child with his twin.
就在湖的中央
A palace in the middle of a lake.
那可怜的人怎么了？
What's the matter with that poor fellow?
自从印度人发生了不幸
Ever since the Indian's misfortune
他发誓不再看其他女人
he took a vow to never look at another squaw.
但是男人一旦蒙住脸，就无法显现她的内心所望
But a man cannot show what's in his heart when he hides his face.
谁，请问你是谁？
Who, may I ask, are you?
大家都叫我蒙面侠
To most I am known as the Masked Bandit.
东南方的灾难大侠？
The Scourge of the Southeast?
正是
That's the one.
但也只有我戴上面具才算是
But that's only when I wear the mask.
你是谁？
Who are you?
护士伊芙琳
Nurse Evelyn.
我曾经是伊芙琳、伊芙列丝、伊芙哈特女士，但是我现在就是…
Once I was Lady Evelyn Everest Everhardt, and now I am simply called...
- 伊芙琳姊妹  - 她不是姊妹
- Sister Evelyn.  - She is not a sister.
不，什么？她是的
Bless you. No. What? Yes, she is.
他没有兄弟姊妹
She doesn't have brothers and sisters.
不，她是修女，跟其他修女一样
No, she's a nun, like these nuns out here.
他转向蒙面侠，说…
And she turned from the Masked Bandit, and she said...
- 我可以跟你坦白说吗？ - 当然
- May I be frank with you?  - Of course.
虽然我将我的生命侍奉主
Although I've dedicated my life to God and goodness
我私底下喜欢朝神父丢橘子
I secretly love throwing oranges at our priest.
向左转两个弯，就是厕所
Take two turns to the left and go to the bathroom.
不，你看了我的纸条
No, you read my note.
你说什么，快去厕所？
What are you talking about? Go to the bathroom.
不
No.
那你怎么知道我对神父丢橘子？
How do you know about the priest and the orange?
每个人都知道你喜欢丢神父橘子
Everybody knows you like throwing oranges at the priest.
每个神父都知道，我不是从你那胡言乱语的纸条得到的讯息
Even the priest knows, but I didn't find that out from your gibberish message.
那不是胡言乱语
It's not gibberish.
她想问你，会停留多久
She wants to ask you how much days I have to stay here.
嗯，我要你待到好了为止
Well, I want you to stay here until you get better.
她的石膏几天后就可以拆除
Her cast will come off in a few days
但我要她待到完全康复为止
but I'd like her to stay here until she's completely recovered.
她说我们在这里待太久了
She wants to say that we are spend here too much times
我们必须离开这里
and we have to leave the city.
不，你告诉她，别再果园里工作
No, well, you just tell her that you shouldn't be working in the groves.
那样太危险了
That at your age it's dangerous
你剩下的日子，只要捡水果就好
and you'll spend the rest of your days picking fruit.
否则她会摔下来，一定会摔下来
And then she'll fall. She surely will fall.
谢谢
Thank you.
- 她怎么说？ - 他说好的
- What did she say?  - She says okay.
- 真的？ - 真的
- Really?  - Really.
亚历珊卓，他问了我一些事情，对吗？
Alexandria, she asked me something, didn't she?
不，那是我们之间的对话
No, that how we speak.
- 你确定？ - 确定
- You sure?  - Sure.
美丽的机器，美丽的机器
Beautiful machina. Beautiful machina.
这真是慷慨的出价啊
It's a very generous offer.
若你看这个数字，比我一年所赚的钱还要多
If you look over here at the number, it's more money than I actually make a year.
我还要加一些东西
I want to add something to it.
别一开始就加这个加那个
Don't start adding stuff to this.
你知道，片厂里面有数不清的律师
You know, the studio's got a building full of lawyers.
跳跃，坠落，撞车
Jumping, falling, crashing.
我是说，牛仔将会赢得那份殊荣
I mean, cowhands are getting all the glory.
无论如何，那是谁的主意？
Whose idea was it anyway?
从火车铁桥跳上一匹马？
Jumping onto a horse from a train bridge?
将这一幕写进合约里面，我就会签署
Add the screening to the contract and I'll sign it.
那要是我死了，钱会怎么处理？
What happens to the money if I die?
罗依，你别再干这种自杀的是晴了
Roy, you need to get off this suicide thing.
让医师好好的为你治疗
Let the doctors finish what they started.
问题不再他的背
Problem is not his back.
而是破碎的新
It's a broken heart.
他需要忘记掉她
He needs to get over her.
我是说，他又不是第一个失去女人的男人
I mean, he's not the first guy to lose a girl.
很抱歉
I'm sorry.
你是个名人
You are someone famous.
他们是这样说得啦
So they tell me.
嘿！孩子！
Hey, kid!
我为你做了这个
I made this for you.
面具后面是谁？
Who's in the mask?
你坐在轮椅上
You in the wheelchair.
很漂亮
It's beautiful.
我会永久保存
I'll keep it forever.
我希望我不会好转
I hope I never get better.
- 为什么？ - 这样我就可以一直跟你在一起
- Why?  - Because I want to stay here with you.
- 嘿！这是今天要给你的  - 真的？
- Hey, this came for you today.  - Really?
- 喜欢巧克力吗？ - 喜欢
- You like chocolate?  - I like it.
- 你要我讲完故事吗？ - 是的
- Do you want me to finish the story?  - Yes.
- 我需要帮忙  - 要帮什么忙？
- I need a favor.  - What kind of favor?
你知道我们的朋友华特？
You know our friend Walt?
- 他不是我朋友  - 他也不是我朋友
- He's not my friend.  - He's not my friend either.
我从他那拿到这钥匙，因为他偷走了我的药丸
I retrieved this key from him because I think he's been stealing my pills.
我想他把它藏在那个小柜子里面
I think he's got them in his cabinet there.
我要你去查看一下
I want you to go check and see if he's got them.
为什么？我已经帮你拿了那瓶药丸
Why? I got you the bottle.
里面的药物，不够帮助我入睡
There weren't enough in there for me to go to sleep.
拜托，做个好强盗
Come on. Be a good bandit.
我不要做强盗
I don't want to be a bandit.
那真糟
That's too bad.
因为欧迪亚斯的城堡是被一个很大的蓝色城市围绕
Because Odious's castle is surrounded by a big blue city.
就是那群强盗要去的地方，最后一战
And that's where the bandits are headed for their final encounter.
这是故事最棒的部份，因为你就要离开了
It's the best part of the story, and since you're leaving soon
我不想让你一辈子都在猜，故事的结局是怎样
I'd hate for you to spend your whole life wondering how it turned out.
- 抽屉里有什么？ - 东西
- What's in the drawer?  - Stuff.
- 什么东西？ - 华特从我这偷走的东西
- What kind of stuff?  - Stuff Walt's been stealing from me.
什么？
What?
你没有去看我也不知道
I won't know until you go look.
- 发誓你会讲完这故事？ - 是呀！
- Promise you'll finish the story?  - Yeah.
是一个棕色的瓶子
It's that brown bottle.
- 这个吗？ - 就是
- This one?  - That's the one.
他从我这偷走的
I think he stole it from me.
那原本是我的
That's mine.
我们要往那去？
Where did we leave off?
他们诉说彼此的秘密
They were telling secrets each other.
我要去找谋害我父亲的人
I'm looking for the man who murdered my father.
蒙面侠说道
The Black Bandit said.
我兄弟，蓝侠…
My brother, the Blue Masked Bandit...
他说…为父亲的死报仇
He said. ...tried to avenge our father's death.
我一直寻求复仇的机会
I've been on a quest for revenge.
被酷刑且吊死
Tortured and hung.
他告诉她一生的事迹，除了欧迪亚斯总督的名字以外
He told her everything about his life except for the name of Governor Odious.
你该走了
You need to leave.
You should go.
但你答应过要讲完故事
But you promised you'll tell me the story.
你深深地打动了我的心，伊芙琳
You've captivated my heart, Evelyn.
那也是为何我再也不能束缚着你
That's why I can no longer keep you in captivity.
我已经深深地爱上了你
I've fallen in love with you.
但我全心全意为了复仇
But I am consumed with revenge.
我不是可以被爱的男人
I'm not a man who can be loved.
当我睡着后，你就要走
When I fall asleep, you gotta go.
明天也不要再来
And don't come back tomorrow.
好的
Okay.
谢谢
Thank you.
- 很抱歉  - 为什么？
- I'm sorry about this.  - Why?
很抱歉
I'm sorry.
为什么？
Why?
我不要你看到我这样
I don't want you to see me like this.
你认为你的魅力俘虏了我？
You think you took me captive?
事实上，你是我的救星
In fact, you're my savior.
我就像是在金色鸟笼里的小鸟
I was like a bird in a golden cage.
一旦解放了我，你就俘虏了我的心
By freeing me, you captured my heart.
让他们亲吻
Make them kiss.
不，我不要让他们接吻
No, I don't want to make them kiss.
为什么？
Why?
因为他们接下来要发现的事情
Because what they're about to find out.
她不该跟我们一起来的
She should have not come with us.
- 为什么？ - 太危险了
- Why?  - It is too dangerous.
要是我们被抓，欧迪亚斯总督一定会杀了她
If we are captured, Governor Odious shall surely kill her.
你说的是欧迪亚斯？
You mentioned Odious?
他就是我发过誓的仇家
He is my sworn enemy.
也是我未婚夫？
And my fianc?
不
No.
我要一直看着你，直到我死为止
I want to look at you until I die.
这世界真是神奇
What a mystery this world.
有一天你爱死他们
One day you love them
隔一天你又想将他们千刀万剐
and the next day you want to kill them a thousand times over.
上帝饶恕他
God forgive him.
幸好我没有吻过你
I'm glad I never kissed you.
她不能死
She can't die.
她还活着！
She's still alive!
她项链下黄金小盒挡住了子但
The solid gold locket stopped the bullet.
“我最亲爱的女儿
"My dearest daughter,
“永远不要为了名、利、权力或是安定而结婚
"never marry for money, fame, power or security.
“一定要顺着你心所想
"Always follow your heart.
“最爱你的父亲”
"Your ever-Ioving father."
小盒上面可以写那么多字？
It says all that on that little locket?
我从无法打开它
I've never been able to open it.
没有人可以打开它，你是第一个
No one's been able to open it. You're the first.
那时，他了解了，她就是他该爱的女人
And he knew that she was the woman he was supposed to love.
拜托，拜托，他们可以接吻了吗？
Please. Please. Now they can kiss-kiss?
是的
Yes.
但是得先结婚
But first, marriage.
然后才能接吻
And then they can kiss.
戒指
The ring.
神秘使者在你掌中发现危险
The Mystic spies danger in your palm.
你服用了太多药物，死亡离你不远了
You've taken too many pills. Death is near.
危险？
Danger?
自杀不是唯一的解决方法
Suicide is not the answer.
他说他知道一种秘密咒语
He says he also knows of a secret chant.
只要我们有险难…
Whenever we're in trouble...
好像是什么“googly-googly？”
Something about "googly-googly?"
他说要是你睡着，就永远不会再醒来
He says if you fall asleep, you will never wake up.
神秘使者是对的
The Mystic was right.
面无表情的神父出卖了他们
The stony-faced priest had betrayed them.
那他们有被救出来吗？
And then they were saved?
不
No.
没有人可以救他们了
There was no one left to save them.
华乐斯？
Wallace?
华乐斯，是你吗？华乐斯？
Wallace, is that you? Wallace?
不，是我
No, it's me.
难怪，这袋子这么重
No wonder the bag was so heavy.
发射！
Shoot!
发射！发射！射死他们，爸爸！
Shoot! Shoot! Shoot them, Daddy!
射死他们！
Shoot them!
爸爸，你认不出我吗？
Daddy, don't you recognize me?
你认不出我吗？是我！
Don't you? It's me!
你认不出我吗？
Don't you recognize me?
- 你是谁？ - 是我，爸爸
- Who are you?  - It's me, Da-da.
- 谁？ - 我！
- Who?  - Me!
- 我女儿？ - 是！你认出我了
- My daughter?  - Yes! You recognize me.
是呀！跟前妻生的女儿
Yeah. My daughter from a previous marriage.
是的
Yes.
因为你长了牙，所以我认不出来
I didn't recognize you because you have teeth.
你现在一定更强壮了
You must be stronger now.
不是睡觉的时候啊
Not the time to sleep now.
Not the time to sleep.
现在不是睡觉的时候啊
It's not time to sleep.
醒醒
Wake up.
醒醒，现在不是睡觉的时候
Wake up. It's not time to sleep now.
醒醒
Wake up.
别假装睡着
Don't pretend to sleep.
醒醒，笑一个，笑一个
Wake up. Laugh, laugh.
不是睡觉的时候
Not the time to sleep.
美洲新蝶
Americana Exotica.
史耐得博士知道这个吗？
Does Dr. Snider know about this?
他还在被观察中，但我想他正在好转中
He was under observation, but I thought he was getting better.
嘿！
Hey!
亚历珊卓，进去！快！
Alexandria, go inside! Go on!
好的，很抱歉，请继续
All right, carry on. Sorry about that.
罗依，醒醒
Roy, wake up. Wake up.
Roy, wake up.
他们要剁掉你，切开你，快醒醒
They're going to cut you up. Gonna chop you up. Wake up.
- 走！快！ - 醒醒
- Go on! Shoo!  - Wake up.
喔！不，不
Oh, no, no, no.
他还是跟往常一样，你知道，微笑，玩弄牙齿
He was his usual self, you know, smiling away, playing with his teeth.
我觉得不太舒服，医生
I just don't feel very well, Doc.
我不知道我怎么了，咳嗽
I don't know what the hell's wrong with me. Cough.
什么，吃药让我精神错乱了吗？
What, am I going delirious from the medication?
我不知道怎么了…
I don't know what the hell...
罗依！
Roy!
罗依，我还以为你死了
Roy, I thought you were dead.
看见两个人，抬着尸体走了
Saw two men, and they were carrying the body away.
当时我还试着捏捏你的脚趾
And then I tried to pinch your toe.
我跑着追你
I run after you,
后来有个医生叫我走，我不得不走开
and after that one of the doctors told me, "Shoo!" and I had to go away.
很抱歉我发誓，但是你…
I'm sorry. I promise, but you...
- 若是你需要，我会带给你更多药丸  - 糖
- I bring you more medicine if you want.  - Sugar.
- 我发誓…  - 他们一直喂他吃糖
- I promise...  - They're giving him sugar.
过来！
Come here!
喔！太好了，你醒了，我带了你的X光片…
Oh, well, that's great, you're awake. I brought your x-rays...
- 嘿！你要看看…  - 医生，那老人死了，你却…
- Hey, you wanna take a look...  - Doc, the old man's dead and you're...
- 嘿，罗依！ - 够了！
- Hey. Roy!  - That's it!
- 你快闭嘴！ - 你才闭嘴！
- Will you shut up, already?  - You shut up!
滚开！你并没有真的生病，华特！他们一再喂你吃糖！
Get out of here! You're not really sick, Walt! They're feeding you sugar!
- 嘿！嘿！嘿！嘿！ - 我受够了你！
- Hey, hey, hey, hey, hey!  - I've had enough of you!
护士！
Nurse!
你说，他们一再喂我吃糖，是什么意思？
What do you mean, they're giving me sugar?
- 给你，医生  - 她身上都弄湿了
- Here you go, Doctor.  - She's wet herself.
带她离开这里
Get her out of here.
回你房间去，看护人！
Go back to your room. Orderlies!
你该睡觉了，亚历珊卓
You should be in bed, Alexandria.
田里面好多萤火虫
There's more fires in the field.
那是煤油火，煤油火让水果不会受冻
It's kerosene. The kerosene stops the fruit from freezing.
不，那是神秘使者
No, it's Mystic.
他会从树里面出来帮助罗依
He's coming out of that tree to help Roy.
小女孩，该睡觉了，不是开玩笑的时刻
I think it's bedtime, young lady. No more time for funny talk.
现在上床去
Into bed now.
也许有一天
And maybe one day
你可以带我到楼下，跟我介绍你的朋友罗依
you can take me downstairs and introduce me to your friend Roy.
我们去楼下，道声晚安？
We go downstairs and say good night?
不，他不能接见访客
No. He's not allowed any visitors.
你朋友，罗依，需要休息
Your friend, Roy, needs to rest.
他失去了女友，非常伤心，需要睡眠
He's very sad. He's lost his girlfriend. He needs to sleep.
但他睡不着，需要药物，他已经没有药丸了
But he can't. He needs medicine to sleep, but he doesn't have any.
问题就在这里
That's the problem.
我确信他们会好好的照顾他
I'm sure they're taking very good care of him.
现在，该睡觉
Now, it's time for bed.
小女孩也需要睡眠的
Little girls need to go to sleep, too.
- 我不小了，我五岁了  - 当然
- I'm not little. I am five.  - Of course.
我忘了
I forgot.
走开！走开！走开！走开！
Googly, googly, googly, go away. Googly, googly, googly, go away.
走开！走开！走开…
Googly, googly. Go away. Googly, googly, googly. Go away.
走开！走开！
Googly, googly. Go away.
走开！走开！走开！
Googly, googly. Googly, googly, googly, go away.
爸爸，他们偷了我们的马
Papa, they steal our horse.
爸爸
Papa,
他们偷了我们的马
they steal our horse.
爸爸，愤怒的人们烧了我们的房子
Papa, angry people burn our home.
人们烧了我们的房子，别出去
They burn our house. Don't go outside.
小偷
Thieves.
暴民乱杀人
Angry people kill.
小偷！
Thieves!
X光片看起来不错
The x-ray seems fine.
- 妈咪！ - 是你给罗依药丸的吗？
- Mommy!  - Were you taking medicine to Roy?
那是你的责任，这也是你要治疗的
That is your responsibility and this is how you treat it.
要好转起来，你需要意志力
To get better, you gotta have the will
你想活下去的意志力
and your own desire to live.
我在次跌了下来
I fell again.
我听说了，每个人都听说了
I heard. Everybody's heard.
你很有铭
You're famous.
他们生气了吗？
Are they angry?
是呀！
Yeah,
但不是针对你
but not at you.
我想要帮你多拿些药丸，但是跌了下来，那是不对的事情…
I try to take more pills, but I fell. It was the wrong thing, and...
- 什么？ - 我将脚放在那上面
- What?  - I put my foot on it when I went up
后来事情就发生了，我坠落了下来
and later on the thing made me go like that and I fell.
我没有跟任何人说我们的秘密
I didn't tell anybody about our secret.
即使他们用针头折磨我
Even when they tortured me with needles.
那个是海盗的旗帜吗？
Is that a pirate's flag?
那是还是不是？
Is that yes or no?
跟我说故事
Tell me the story.
你需要休息，我该走了
I should go. You need your rest.
但是我想讲话
But I want to talk.
- 我知道  - 你答应过的
- I know you do.  - You promised.
那故事是假的，只是为了让你帮我做事情
The story was just a trick to get you to do something for me.
- 什么？ - 我…
- What?  - I was...
但我需要听故事
But I need the story.
你去找别人讲给你听
You should ask someone else.
对我而言，没有什么快乐式结局
There's no happy ending with me.
我仍然想听
I still want to know.
问你的朋友护士伊芙琳，她讲的故事会更棒
Ask your friend, Nurse Evelyn, she'll tell it better than I will.
我不想有她在故事里面！
I don't want her in the story!
她还好啊
She's okay.
喔！她不是真的爱欧迪亚斯总督
Oh, she doesn't really love Governor Odious.
她是假装的
She's just pretending.
我看过她跟医院的人在一起
I saw her with one of the hospital men.
她是假装爱你
She was just pretending to love you.
跟你的女友一样
Just like your girlfriend.
我懂了
I see.
欧迪亚斯总督跟护士伊芙琳！
Governor Odious with Nurse Evelyn!
她是对的
She's right.
她是对的！
She's right!
我们不需要她
We don't need her.
她是不可信任的
She can't be trusted.
你对他们掏心掏肺，但是他们只想要你的钱
You give them your heart, but all they really want is your wallet.
早晚有天，她会为了更有钱的人而离开
Sooner or later she's gonna leave him for a richer man.
是个陷阱
Is a trap.
- 我懂了  - 我不喜欢
- I understand.  - I don't like it.
谢谢你告诉我
Thank you for telling me.
对我们简直就是自杀
Is a suicide. For all of us.
我们走吧
We're going.
嘿！印度人，你说自杀是什么意思？
Hey, Indian, what means suicide?
华乐斯？华乐斯！
Wallace? Wallace!
华乐斯！
Wallace!
华乐斯，你在做什么？
Wallace, what are you doing?
华乐斯，快下来好吗？
Wallace, please will you come down?
快，现在不是玩耍时间
Please, this really isn't the time.
华乐斯，拜托！华乐斯，下来好吗？
Wallace, please! Wallace, will you come down?
华乐斯！
Wallace!
华乐斯，你做了什么？
Wallace, what did you do?
美洲新蝶！
Americana Exotica!
真美丽！
It's beautiful!
他真的死了吗？
Does he really died?
走吧！
Let's go!
我已经精疲力竭了！
I'm all washed-up!
- 达尔文叔叔，有暴民  - 别离开我，朋友
- Uncle Darwin, there's angry people.  - Don't leave me, my friend.
我会告诉每个人说，那是你的发现
I'll tell everyone they were your idea.
他们会发现我只是个骗子！
They're going to find out I'm a fraud!
来吧！射啊，畜生！
Go on! Shoot, you animals!
杀死达尔文，他们会给你们很高的报酬
They'll pay you well for Darwin's hide.
他也死了
He died, too.
华乐斯也是吗？
And Wallace, too?
他真的死了吗？
Did he really died?
是呀！对华乐斯而言，何尝不能算快乐的死
Yeah, and in Wallace's case, happily so.
生死也是大自然的法则
It was the natural order of things.
万物皆会死
All things must die.
去她的！
Damn it all!
退后！退后！
Back! Get back!
卡--蹦
Kaboom.
若是要成就些什么…
If you want something done...
下去那里！
Get down there!
…你要自己去做
...you have to do it yourself.
下去那里，畜生们！
Get down there, you animals!
将他们带上来！
And bring them up here!
我不喜欢这样，我不喜欢这个故事
I don't like this! I don't like this story.
我们为何要逃跑？
Why are we running away?
为何路易奇要同归于尽？
Why did Luigi kill himself?
为何不跟我们一起来？
Why did not he come with us?
跟人们一样生活？
And live as half a man?
他无法那样做
He couldn't do that.
他投降了
He gave up.
不是尽如人意，是吗？
It's not very satisfying, is it?
他也这么认为
He didn't think so either.
拜托，神秘使者
Please, the Mystic.
为什么？他们为何要杀神秘使者？
Why? Why are they killing the Mystic?
我们应该去救他
We need to go help him.
神秘使者！
Mystic!
- 嘿！ - 神秘使者！
- Hey!  - Mystic!
曲线，曲线，曲线，曲线
Googly, googly, googly, googly, googly, googly.
很抱歉！很抱歉！
I'm sorry! I'm sorry!
很抱歉！
I'm sorry!
很抱歉
I'm sorry.
曲线，曲线，曲线！
Googly, googly, googly!
没事
It's okay.
印度人！
Indian!
起来！
Up!
救命！
Help!
不，不，不，不
No, no, no, no, no.
No, no, no, no!
为何你要杀每个人？
Why are you killing everybody?
为何你要每个人都死？
Why are you making everybody die?
这是我的故事
It's my story.
也是我的啊
Mine too.
将他们带上来！
Bring them up here!
留活口！
Alive!
我们在这
We are here.
活着
Alive.
罗依！
Roy!
别看着她
Don't look at her.
- 他也是跟欧迪亚斯一伙的  - 安静
- She is also with Odious.  - Quiet.
- 跟你女友一样  - 闭嘴
- Just like your girlfriend.  - Shut up.
不！
No!
你女友跟欧迪亚斯一起来…看你了
Your girlfriend came with Odious to see you...
强盗们进入了欧迪亚斯的花园…
The bandit entered Odious's garden...
但是她站在车子里面，而且她…
But she stood in the car and she...
- 但是看不见欧迪亚斯的踪影  - 欧迪亚斯…
- But Odious was nowhere to be seen.  - And Odious...
当强盗们跑过欧迪亚斯躲藏的地方，欧迪亚斯打断了他的鼻子！
As the bandit ran past Odious' hiding place, Odious cracked him in the nose!
不，等等，请等等！
No, but wait a little. Wait, please!
后来他沉到了池底
So he sank to the bottom of the pool.
一点也没有试着游泳
He didn't even try to swim.
- 一切都是你杜撰的  - 不，我没有
- You are making this up.  - No, I'm not.
他开始下沉，就要死亡
And he started to sink and he was dying.
让他活着
Let him live.
起来！
Get up!
罗依，起来，战斗！
Roy, get up and fight!
起来！
Get up!
喔！真丢脸！看，妈的！
Oh, what a shame! Look, God damn it!
起来！
Get up!
看着他！看着他！
Look at him! Look at him!
起来！
Get up!
- 我要你看他究竟有多可悲  - 我站不起来！
- I want you to see how pathetic he really is.  - I can't get up!
- 起来！ - 我站不起来！
- Get up!  - I can't get up!
- 老天啊，这水只有及腰深  - 起来，爸爸！
- For God's sake, the water's only waist high.  - Get up, Daddy!
我不是你父亲
I'm not your father.
多可悲啊！看看他！他是个要瘾者！
How pathetic! Look at him! He's a drug addict!
你父亲是个懦夫
Your father is a coward.
一无是处的懦夫！
A useless good-for-nothing!
爸爸，起来！
Dad, get up!
他赢不了的！
He can't win!
因为我们的蒙面侠是个懦夫！
That's because our Masked Bandit's a coward!
是呀！他绝对不会发誓
Yeah, he never took an oath.
- 骗徒，懦夫  - 你说晃！
- A fake, he's a liar and a coward.  - You're lying!
不，他祝你好运
No. He had his fingers crossed.
他必须死
He has to die.
我不相信你
I don't believe you.
他就要死了
He was dying.
别杀他
Don't kill him.
- 你需要的话我会给你带来更多药丸的  - 爸爸，起来！
- I'll bring you more pills if you want.  - Dad, get up!
- 别杀他  - 他已经无牵无挂了
- Don't kill him.  - There's nothing left for him.
他女儿
His daughter.
他也不是父亲
He wasn't her father, either.
她爱他
She loves him.
她会活下来，她还年轻
She'll survive. She's young.
我不要你死
I don't want you to die.
别杀他
Don't kill him.
让他活
Let him live.
别杀他
Don't kill him.
发誓？别祝福我
Promise? And don't cross your fingers.
我保证
I promise.
让我看你的手
Show me your hands.
看见没？
See?
别再打斗了
No more fighting.
他要去找他的女儿，好的
He needs to go to his daughter. It's okay.
没事，没事，一切结束了
It's okay. It's all right. It's over now.
亲亲我
Give me a kiss.
罗依
Roy,
你真的了解，这只是看你是否真的爱我的测试，对吗？
you do realize it was all a test to see if you truly loved me, don't you?
我们终于可以顺着我们的真心而行了
We're finally free to follow our hearts.
当然是
By all means.
顺你的真心而行
Follow your heart.
我觉得不太舒服
I'm not feeling very well.
我们是奇特的一对，是吗？
We're a strange pair, aren't we?
行动，行动，行动，行动
Action, action, action, action.
这就是我们将要制作的东西
So, this is the kind of trash we're gonna be making now.
人们从屋顶跳下，从桥上、马背上跳下
People jumping off buildings, bridges, horses.
我错过了什么吗？
Did I just miss something?
就这样？
That was it?
那就是他的绝技？
That was his big stunt?
他连跳马背都没有
He didn't even use that horse thing.
我将老人的牙齿放在那里，因为我认为
I put old man's teeth there because I think that
神秘使者从树木里出来，这样会长成一株特别的树
the Mystic comes out of the tree and it will grow a special orange tree.
亚历珊卓！亚历珊卓！
Alexandria! Alexandria!
我们就会有里面长牙齿的橘子，长牙齿的橘子
And we'll have oranges inside with teeths, with teeth inside.
我出院以后，我非常想念罗依
When I get out from the hospital, I miss Roy very much.
我母亲告诉我，他有演出电影
My mother told me that he plays in pictures
他会做其他演员做不到的动作
and he does things that the other actors cannot do
像是爬到什么上面
like falling and hitting
然后掉下来
and when they climb on something, when they...
我原本不相信，直到我亲眼看见
I didn't believe my mother, but then I saw him.
我一遍又一遍的看那片子
I watch the picture again and again and again
要确认那是罗依，真的是罗依！
and to make sure that was Roy, and was Roy!
后来，我超爱电影，所有电影
And then, I like the action from all the pictures
因为我知道，罗依会演出所有的高处坠落等等特技
because I know that Roy is making all the falling and hitting and climbing
他爬到梯子上
and he was on the stairs
上上下下，上上下下的
and he was going up and down and up and down.
还有从火车上跳下，跳上车子…
And he was falling from the train and he was taking the car...
从单车上跳下，从大房子屋顶跳下
And he was falling from the bicycle and from a big house.
那是华乐斯！
It was Wallace!
他跟绳子一起坠落
He was falling with the rope
他被打，然后将会…
and he was hit and he was going...
“谢谢，谢谢，非常感谢！”
"Thank you, thank you, thank you very much!"